<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
	<id>io.github.lockekk.Dshare-hid</id>
	<metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
	<project_license>GPL-2.0-only</project_license>
	<name>DShare-HID</name>
	<developer id="io.github.lockekk.Dshare-hid">
		<name>DShare-HID Developers</name>
	</developer>
	<summary>Hardware-accelerated keyboard and mouse sharing</summary>
	<summary xml:lang="zh_CN">带硬件加速的键鼠共享工具</summary>
	<summary xml:lang="ko">키보드 및 마우스 공유 소프트웨어</summary>
	<description>
		<p>
			Use the keyboard, mouse, or trackpad of one computer to control nearby computers, and work seamlessly between them.
		</p>
		<p xml:lang="zh_CN">
			使用一台计算机的键盘、鼠标或触控板来控制附近的其它计算机，并在它们之间无缝工作。
		</p>
		<p xml:lang="ko">
			한 대의 컴퓨터에 연결된 키보드, 마우스 또는 트랙패드로 주변의 다른 컴퓨터를 제어하고, 컴퓨터 사이를 끊김 없이 오가며 작업할 수 있습니다.
		</p>
	</description>
	<launchable type="desktop-id">io.github.lockekk.Dshare-hid.desktop</launchable>
	<url type="homepage">https://github.com/lockekk/dshare-hid</url>
	<url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/lockekk/dshare-hid/issues</url>
	<url type="faq">https://github.com/lockekk/dshare-hid/wiki</url>
	<url type="help">https://github.com/lockekk/dshare-hid/wiki</url>
	<url type="vcs-browser">https://github.com/lockekk/dshare-hid</url>
	<url type="contribute">https://github.com/lockekk/dshare-hid/wiki</url>
	<screenshots>
		<screenshot type="default">
			<image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/lockekk/dshare-hid/main/doc/images/main_ui.png</image>
			<caption>DShare-HID Main UI</caption>
		</screenshot>
		<screenshot>
			<image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/lockekk/dshare-hid/main/doc/images/device_config.png</image>
			<caption>Device Configuration</caption>
		</screenshot>
	</screenshots>
	<provides> <id>io.github.lockekk.Dshare-hid.desktop</id> </provides>
	<categories>
		<category>Utility</category>
	</categories>
	<keywords>
		<keyword>Input</keyword>
		<keyword xml:lang="zh_CN">输入</keyword>
		<keyword xml:lang="ko">입력</keyword>
		<keyword>Sharing</keyword>
		<keyword xml:lang="zh_CN">共享</keyword>
		<keyword xml:lang="ko">공유</keyword>
		<keyword translate="no">KVM</keyword>
		<keyword translate="no">Synergy</keyword>
	</keywords>
	<branding>
		<color type="primary" scheme_preference="light">#dddddd</color>
		<color type="primary" scheme_preference="dark">#555555</color>
	</branding>
	<content_rating type="oars-1.0" />
	<releases>
		<release version="1.26.0" date="2026-02-16" urgency="high">
			<description>
				<p>This stable release fixes known issues and adds a few new features, For the full changelog, see the release page.</p>
				<ul>
					<li>New: Korean(ko) translation</li>
					<li>New: Option to start in the "locked to computer" state</li>
					<li>New: Option to show the version in the windows title</li>
					<li>New: Clients can now use a list hostnames or ips for the server address</li>
					<li>New: Client options are in a new client configuration dialog</li>
					<li>New: Provide a more accurate suggested IP, Update as network info changes if needed.</li>
					<li>New: Add a simple search to the log</li>
					<li>New: Lookup host name with IP4 or IP6</li>
					<li>New: Replace broken scroll speed with a scroll scaling options</li>
					<li>Fix: Horizontal scrolling is working again on all platforms</li>
					<li>Fix: Key repeat events are now sent as repeat not press and release</li>
					<li>Fix: Deskflow-core correctly blocks new instances when run without the `--new-instance` option</li>
					<li>Fix: Server Mode, Only use the external config path if the option is enabled</li>
					<li>Fix: Allow comma and semicolon to be used in the hotkey configuration</li>
					<li>Fix: Gui can crash when clearing settings in debug mode</li>
					<li>Fix: Mouse Back and Forward buttons are now working (again) on all platforms</li>
					<li>Fix: macOS, crash when the log is opened and the gui minimized</li>
					<li>Fix: macOS, restore Preferences menu entry when the application is using non english language</li>
					<li>Fix: macOS, try icon was not showing when in `Colorful` mode</li>
					<li>Fix: macOS, do not allow the os to kill deskflow for memory reasons</li>
					<li>Fix: macOS, possible server crash when a client disconnects abruptly</li>
					<li>Fix: macOS, possible crash on screen wake / screen saver activation</li>
					<li>Fix: macOS, Wrong keys send when using "RIME" input method</li>
					<li>Fix: Windows, possible crash when the daemon is started for the first time</li>
					<li>Use `Computer` in place of `Screen` to indicate we work with Computers display layout and not individual screens attached</li>
					<li>Clean and update the settings when starting up.</li>
					<li>Do not show client connection error messages dialogs if the gui is hidden</li>
					<li>Use Qt 6.9.3 for Intel Mac builds.</li>
					<li>Windows: Use ICU dlls from the host system</li>
					<li>Code continues to be cleaned of unused methods and updated to modern C++</li>
					<li>Consolidate Debug levels to remove DEBUG3-5 levels</li>
				</ul>
			</description>
			<url>https://github.com/deskflow/deskflow/releases/tag/v1.26.0</url>
		</release>
	</releases>
</component>
